<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Defs>
  <XenotypeDef>
    <defName>Glintscale</defName>
    <label>glintscale</label>
    <description>Powerful, red hot, and extremely avaricious, the glintscale is a strange, physics defying dragon-like xenohuman, believed to have been altered by archites. They are masters of melee combat, excellent at range combat, and are genetically predisposed towards crafting, to ensure that they can sate their own demand for masterwork and legendary possessions. Their desire for wealth is so great they need to regularly consume gold and silver to power their altered body, and they constantly covet the best of the best. The glintscale's seemingly impossible powers use a material called Aurum, which is actually a very tiny, extremely conductive mechanite that is fabricated from precious metals. Aurum can augment the body's systems and be released to produce seemingly miraculous electric and pyrotechnic phenomena, which glintscales use to dramatic effect.\n\nIt is believed that the first glintscale was a treasure hunter who discovered a seemingly dead transcendent world, abandoned by its archotech creator. He scoured its depths, taking as much unthinkable machinery as he could, until he realized far too late that the world wasn't as abandoned as he once thought. Before he knew it, he had been totally changed on the genetic level, and his greed had been taken to an impossible level.</description>
    <descriptionShort>Powerful, red hot, and extremely avaricious, the glintscale is a strange, physics defying dragon-like creature, believed to have been altered by archites. They are masters of melee combat, excellent at range combat, and are genetically predisposed towards crafting, to ensure that they can sate their own demand for masterwork and legendary possessions. Their desire for wealth is so great they need to regularly consume gold and silver to power their altered body, and they constantly covet the best of the best.</descriptionShort>
    <iconPath>UI/Xenotypes/Glintscale</iconPath>
    <soundDefOnImplant>PawnBecameSanguophage</soundDefOnImplant>
    <combatPowerFactor>7</combatPowerFactor>
    <displayPriority>-1001</displayPriority>
    <genes>
      <li>BTEMy_AurumThirst</li>
      <li>BTEMy_DraconicNose</li>
      <li>BTEMy_DraconicTail</li>
      <li>BTEMy_DraconicHorns</li>
      <li>BTEMy_DraconicWings</li>
      <li>BTEMy_BlazingClaws</li>
      <li>FireResistant</li>
      <li>Ageless</li>
      <li>Hair_BrightRed</li>
      <li>AptitudeStrong_Construction</li>
      <li>PsychicAbility_Deaf</li>
      <li>BTEMy_AurumDetonation</li>
      <li>MeleeDamage_Strong</li>
      <li>TotalHealing</li>
      <li>FireSpew</li>
      <li>DiseaseFree</li>
	  <li>AptitudeTerrible_Animals</li>
	  <li>AptitudeTerrible_Plants</li>
	  <li>VoiceRoar</li>
	  <li>Mood_Pessimist</li>
      <li>BTEMy_AdamantScales</li>
      <li>BTEMy_AdamantScalesNoGraphic</li>
      <li>WoundHealing_Fast</li>
	  <li>Sleepy</li>
      <li>AptitudeRemarkable_Melee</li>
      <li>AptitudeStrong_Crafting</li>
      <li>ArchiteMetabolism</li>
      <li>Aggression_HyperAggressive</li>
	  <li>Skin_DeepRed</li>
      <li>Robust</li>
      <li>Unstoppable</li>
	  <li>MinTemp_SmallIncrease</li>
	  <li>BTEMy_AvariceInstinct</li>
    </genes>
	</XenotypeDef>
  <XenotypeDef>
    <defName>Ashfeather</defName>
    <label>ashfeather</label>
    <description>Ashfeathers are phoenix like xenohumans, who must consume gold and silver to power their abilities. Their aurum thirst is stabilized however, and it won't passively decrease, but it is also harder for them to gain aurum. They are incredible healers and speakers, and their aurum abilities revolve around healing the mind and body. They are genetically incapable of combat, are vulnerable to damage, and their bodies are somewhat more vulnerable to disease. They possess higher than usual psychic ability, and work well with animals and people alike. The ashfeather has fine control over a material called Aurum, which is actually a very tiny, extremely conductive mechanite that is fabricated from precious metals. Aurum can augment the body's systems and be released to produce seemingly miraculous electric and pyrotechnic phenomena, which ashfeathers use for subtle but profound purposes.\n\nIt is believed that the first ashfeather was created after extensive bioengineering of a glintscale in an attempt to pacify one genetically. The experiment was a resounding success, and the ashfeather came to be, an xenotype that can harness aurum without eventually succumbing towards berserk tendencies.</description>
    <descriptionShort>Ashfeathers are phoenix like xenohumans, who must consume gold and silver to power their abilities. Their aurum thirst is stabilized however, and it won't passively decrease, but it is also harder for them to gain aurum. They are incredible healers and speakers, and their aurum abilities revolve around healing the mind and body. They are genetically incapable of combat, are vulnerable to damage, and their bodies are somewhat more vulnerable to disease. They possess higher than usual psychic ability, and work well with animals and people alike.</descriptionShort>
    <iconPath>UI/Xenotypes/Ashfeather</iconPath>
    <soundDefOnImplant>PawnBecameSanguophage</soundDefOnImplant>
    <combatPowerFactor>999999</combatPowerFactor>
    <displayPriority>-1002</displayPriority>
    <genes>
      <li>BTEMy_AurumThirst</li>
      <li>BTEMy_PhoenixNose</li>
      <li>BTEMy_PhoenixTail</li>
      <li>BTEMy_PhoenixCrest</li>
      <li>BTEMy_PhoenixWings</li>
      <li>BTEMy_Cauterize</li>
      <li>BTEMy_AurumStabilizer</li>
	  <li>MoveSpeed_Quick</li>
      <li>BTEMy_PurgeMemory</li>
      <li>FireResistant</li>
	  <li>Delicate</li>
      <li>Ageless</li>
      <li>Hair_SandyBlonde</li>
      <li>Hair_BaldOnly</li>
      <li>KindInstinct</li>
      <li>TotalHealing</li>
      <li>FireSpew</li>
	  <li>Immunity_Weak</li>
      <li>PsychicAbility_Enhanced</li>
      <li>DiseaseFree</li>
	  <li>AptitudeTerrible_Melee</li>
	  <li>AptitudeTerrible_Shooting</li>
	  <li>AptitudeTerrible_Mining</li>
	  <li>ViolenceDisabled</li>
	  <li>Furskin</li>
	  <li>Mood_Optimist</li>
      <li>Pain_Extra</li>
      <li>AptitudeRemarkable_Medicine</li>
      <li>AptitudeStrong_Social</li>
      <li>AptitudeStrong_Animals</li>
      <li>ArchiteMetabolism</li>
	  <li>MinTemp_SmallIncrease</li>
    </genes>
  </XenotypeDef>
  
  <XenotypeDef MayRequire="biotexpans.mammalia">
    <defName>Tailbinder</defName>
    <label>tailbinder</label>
    <description>A strange fox-like xenotype with multiple tails, the tailbinder is a creature whose consciousness is partially separate from their physical bodies. This grants them immense psychic powers, but they rely on the psychic energy of others to survive. This energy is cultivated primarily through voluntary worship, as a result this xenotype is often treated as a god. Tailbinders are attuned to the natural world, and are capable of delivering blessings and curses to those they deem fit. Their physical bodies are weakened as a result of their reliance on psychic power, however.</description>
    <descriptionShort>Tailbinders are attuned to the natural world, and are capable of delivering blessings and curses to those they deem fit. Their physical bodies are weaked as a result of their reliance on psychic power.</descriptionShort>
    <iconPath>UI/Xenotypes/Tailbinder</iconPath>
    <displayPriority>-1003</displayPriority>
    <genes>
      <li>Ageless</li>
      <li>ArchiteMetabolism</li>
      <li>TotalHealing</li>
      <li>DarkVision</li>
	  <li>BTEMa_SensitiveWhiskers</li>
      <li>BTEMa_Nose_Lupine</li> 
      <li>BTEMa_SharpClaws</li>
	  <li>BTEMa_RabbitsIntuition</li>
      <li>Hair_SandyBlonde</li>
      <li>BTEMy_ReveredEmbodiment</li>
      <li>BTEMy_CurseUser</li>
      <li>BTEMy_BlessingUser</li>
      <li>BTEMy_Punish</li>
      <li>BTEMa_VulpineEars</li>
      <li>AptitudeStrong_Plants</li>
      <li>AptitudeStrong_Animals</li>
      <li>AptitudeStrong_Artistic</li>
      <li>AptitudePoor_Melee</li>
      <li>BTEMy_MultiFoxTail</li>
      <li>BTEMy_ReverenceGreed</li>
      <li>Furskin</li>
      <li>PsychicAbility_Enhanced</li>
	  <li>Delicate</li>
      <li>Pain_Extra</li>
    </genes>
  </XenotypeDef>
</Defs>